PETER EVANS

PROFILE

Physics graduate experienced in using Python as part of a complete data science life cycle - initially to collect, cleanse and analyse data before undertaking feature engineering and model building (regression, classification and clustering on both structured and text data). Example projects available on portfolio website.

Available to start work immediately.

EDUCATION

University of Buckingham

2021

MSc in Applied Data Science with Distinction.

University of Bristol

2015 - 2019

MSci in Physics with First-Class Honours.

Royal Latin School

2008 - 2015

AAB in Physics, Mathematics and Chemistry A Levels respectively.

7 A*s, 3 As and 1 B achieved at GCSE level.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Digital Analytics Coordinator

Oct 2021 - Dec 2021

University of Buckingham

- · Responsible for building insightful, dynamically updating dashboards using both Tableau and Google Data Studio in order to optimise return on investment of digital marketing activity.
- · Required a particular focus on regular expressions in order to filter user-inputted data.

English as a Foreign Language Teacher

Oct 2019 - Mar 2020

American Language Academy

- · Year abroad working as a teacher enabled me to develop many soft skills, especially communication and leadership.
- · Primarily worked with business executives to improve their English skills for the professional environment.

Technical Intern - Cyber Insights GCHQ

Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

- · Studied various technologies of the cyber field at the organisation's annual summer school, covering topics such as secure coding, reverse engineering and pen testing.
- · Took part in a variety of workshops to practise cyber skills for example, crashing a virtual machine with malware or using a weakness in an IoT device to break into its network.

Manager

Mar 2017 - Jun 2018

InHouse Media

· Co-managed a student-led video production company that created promotional videos for local businesses.

Various Hospitality Positions

2015 - 2020

Mutliple Agencies

· Temporary roles in order to be able to fund studies, which required working in very fast-paced environments.

SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES

Tech Stack Python (NumPy, Pandas, scikit-learn, BeautifulSoup, Matplotlib, spaCy, NLTK, PySpark),

SQL, GitHub, Tableau, Google Data Studio, Google Analytics, Excel, Word, LaTeX.

Other Limited working proficiency level in Spanish. Full UK driving licence.